<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><updated>2020-08-06T19:28:12+02:00</updated><id>https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ietsism</title><subtitle>A blog about anything that occupies my mind</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How iPhone or iOS could be improved</title><link href="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/how-iphone-or-ios-could-be-improved/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How iPhone or iOS could be improved"/><published>2020-08-05T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-05T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/how-iphone-or-ios-could-be-improved</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/how-iphone-or-ios-could-be-improved/">&lt;p&gt;I like my iPhone. It has almost been a decade since I have started using one. Before that I owned a 2nd-gen iPod Touch that came with iOS 2. So, with the exception of the first iPhone OS release, I have worked with and experienced all iOS versions on various different hardware (iPod, iPhone, and iPad). In these years I have ran into the limitations of the software on several occasions. In this article I would like to share 10 of these limitations and my proposed fixes. Hopefully Apple will implement these one day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the time of writing the latest version of iOS was &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;13.6&lt;/code&gt;. I believe these limitations were still present, at least up to that version.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;low-battery-notifications&quot;&gt;Low battery notifications&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am sure you have all encountered these; persistent pop-up notifications about your battery either being below a 20% or 10% charge. The only way to get rid of these notifications is by pressing the &lt;em&gt;Dismiss&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Close&lt;/em&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: include setting to turn these notifications off.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt; &lt;picture&gt; &lt;source srcset=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ios/battery.webp&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ios/battery.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Persistent low battery notification on iOS&quot; /&gt; &lt;/picture&gt; &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Persistent low battery notification on iOS&lt;/figcaption&gt; &lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ios/battery&quot; alt=&quot;Persistent low battery notification on iOS&quot;&gt;--&gt; &lt;/figure&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;phone-call-recording&quot;&gt;Phone call recording&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;A feature I used to use on my old Sony Ericsson dumbphone&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; was recording phone calls. Especially when receiving important phone calls, being able to record them and listening to them at a later point tends to be useful. (or maybe you would just like to record your own or the other person’s voice.) However, it seems like in some countries, like the US of A, this is not allowed without the other person’s consent. Nonetheless, we know that Apple is open to adapting their products to various regions. (or is Apple forced to by a certain Asian country?)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; But if so, why not enable call recording as well for certain countries?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: you guessed it, incorporate an option to record phone calls (preferably with a button the call screen).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;automatic-download-of-updates&quot;&gt;Automatic download of updates&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I believe this has been fixed nowadays&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of my pet peeves is that iOS tends to download updates when your device is connected to Wi-Fi and is charging. On my 16GB iPhone (:weary:) this meant: 1) random notifications about iPhone reaching its maximum storage capacity, and 2) me going into &lt;em&gt;Settings&lt;/em&gt; to remove the 1GB+ update.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: provide setting to not automatically download (or is it &lt;em&gt;force&lt;/em&gt;?) updates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;incoming-call-screen&quot;&gt;Incoming call screen&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Something I encounter regularly: someone (or some &lt;em&gt;bot&lt;/em&gt;) trying to reach you while you do not want to answer. There is no way to get rid of the incoming call screen unless the other person hangs up or you hit the lock button twice. However, when you do the latter, the other person will receive a busy signal. In case of telemarketers this means that they know the number is in use. For your mother-in-law it means she knows what you are up to. I just want to keep on doing whatever I was doing, ignoring the incoming call without the other side knowing about it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: include option to get out of the incoming call screen unnoticeably.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt; &lt;picture&gt; &lt;source srcset=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ios/call_screen.webp&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ios/call_screen.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;A wild call screen appears!&quot; /&gt; &lt;/picture&gt; &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A wild call screen appears!&lt;/figcaption&gt; &lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/ios/call_screen&quot; alt=&quot;A wild call screen appears!&quot;&gt;--&gt; &lt;/figure&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;ios-version-numbering&quot;&gt;iOS version numbering&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The version numbering of iOS is a bit awkward. At first I thought that Apple wanted to get to iOS 10 ASAP, to have the same version number as its Mac equivalent: OS X (OS 10). But no, Apple changed OS X to &lt;em&gt;macOS&lt;/em&gt;, ditching the version number implicitly. (maybe because of Windows 10?) Apple releases a new version every year. The yearly release cycle seems a bit artificial. Sometimes new versions release with not-so-major changes, at least that is how it appears to the naked eye. The forced version numbering also has another caveat: it renders software for non-supported hardware, like iPhone 5, to be stuck on something ugly such as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;10.3.4&lt;/code&gt;, likely forever.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: stick with same major version number for over 1 year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;safari-web-browser&quot;&gt;Safari web browser&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Safari might be a good web browser to some, others dub it the new Internet Explorer.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; That can not be a compliment.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Although it may appear like you can install Chrome or Firefox on your device, under the hood this is not the case: they all use the Safari engine. Every browser on iOS is thus limited in some way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: allow third party browsers and &lt;em&gt;full&lt;/em&gt; support for extensions.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;flashlight-during-video-calls&quot;&gt;Flashlight during video calls&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ever video called in a darker room? Good luck trying to turn on your flashlight when you want to show your mom your report card! iOS, flashlights, and (video) calls do not go together. Is it a hardware limitation? Was it Steve Jobs’ idea?&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; We can only guess.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: allow turning on the flashlight when video calling.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;headphone-jack&quot;&gt;Headphone jack&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Enough has been written about this already. There is/was enough physical room.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Though technically not a software issue, the fact that iOS still supports a headphone jack through its software (if you buy a $9 adapter&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that is) is why it makes my list.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: Apple drill a 3.5 mm hole in the bottom (or the top) of your devices and make sure it can communicate with wired headphones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;vibrator&quot;&gt;Vibrator&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since iPhone 7’s &lt;em&gt;Taptic Engine&lt;/em&gt; that replaced the traditional vibration motor I oversleep and miss calls more than ever. My older iPhones used to almost vibrate through my nightstand when the alarm would go off, my newer iPhones sound feeble. Again, more of a hardware issue, but perhaps could be solved with a clever software fix.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: let iOS unleash Taptic Engine’s true character and send all battery power to Taptic Engine for a loud roar.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;bluetooth-and-wi-fi-buttons&quot;&gt;Bluetooth and Wi-Fi buttons&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since iOS 11, the Bluetooth and Wi-Fi buttons in &lt;em&gt;Control Center&lt;/em&gt; actually leave your Bluetooth and Wi-Fi on. The buttons merely allow you to quickly connect and disconnect.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Even worse, Bluetooth and Wi-Fi unexpectedly turn on in certain scenarios, even when you “disabled” them with the buttons. This is a security and privacy risk.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:10&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:10&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (Apple and others can track your location this way.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:11&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:11&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fix: let buttons work how they used to prior to iOS 11.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;last-words&quot;&gt;Last words&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Even a near-perfect product has its flaws. As software is not the obstacle to fix these limitations, I am sure that some of them will get fixed in the future. And for those that would not get fixed, Apple might have a good reason not to. What do you feel could be improved? Let us discuss it in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;A phone capable of recording calls was my old Sony Ericsson K750i that came with this awesome &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/WbNJ5fbUdo4&quot;&gt;demo video&lt;/a&gt; installed &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wakephone.com/2019/02/differences-between-the-u-s-a-china-and-japanese-versions-you-need-to-know-before-buying-iphones-in-bulk/&quot;&gt;in China no FaceTime audio calls can be placed&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/nektro/safari-is-the-new-internet-explorer-1df0&quot;&gt;Safari is the new Internet Explorer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ihateinternetexplorer.com/&quot;&gt;For those of you who hate Internet Explorer (or want to know why it sucks)&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the time being, to block ads on your home network, install &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/&quot;&gt;Pi-hole®&lt;/a&gt;, the best thing since sliced bread &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since apparently Steve Jobs was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inc.com/tommy-mello/according-to-steve-jobs-only-way-to-succeed-is-to-abandon-1000-good-ideas.html&quot;&gt;the killer of thousands of ideas&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Watch &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/utfbE3_uAMA&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; video if you want to know more &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MMX62AM/A/lightning-to-35-mm-headphone-jack-adapter&quot;&gt;Something that should not be necessary&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Read more about Bluetooth and Wi-Fi buttons at &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT208086&quot;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:10&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Read more about risks related these buttons in &lt;em&gt;Control Center&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2017/10/ios-11s-misleading-ish-setting-bluetooth-and-wi-fi-bad-user-security&quot;&gt;EFF&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:10&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:11&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2019/9/19/20867286/ios-13-bluetooth-permission-privacy-feature-apps&quot;&gt;Tracking could be done through Bluetooth&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:11&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ietsism</name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="iPhone"/><category term="iOS"/><category term="improvements"/><summary type="html">I like my iPhone. It has almost been a decade since I have started using one. Before that I owned a 2nd-gen iPod Touch that came with iOS 2. So, with the exception of the first iPhone OS release, I have worked with and experienced all iOS versions on various different hardware (iPod, iPhone, and iPad). In these years I have ran into the limitations of the software on several occasions. In this article I would like to share 10 of these limitations and my proposed fixes. Hopefully Apple will implement these one day.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/assets/images/posts/ios/iphone.jpg"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/assets/images/posts/ios/iphone.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Elon Musk is not an engineer</title><link href="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/why-elon-musk-is-not-an-engineer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Elon Musk is not an engineer"/><published>2020-08-03T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-08-03T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/why-elon-musk-is-not-an-engineer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/why-elon-musk-is-not-an-engineer/">&lt;p&gt;Search online for Elon Musk and one of the first things you will find is his Wikipedia page.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The first sentence reads as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Elon Reeve Musk&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size:85%;&quot;&gt;FRS&lt;/span&gt; (/ˈiːlɒn/; born June 28, 1971) is an &lt;span class=&quot;evidence&quot;&gt;engineer&lt;/span&gt;, industrial designer, technology entrepreneur and philanthropist.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Though Elon Musk might have achieved a lot, an engineer he is not. As an engineer myself, who has spent years studying, this does not feel right. Especially with fake news being omnipresent online, Wikipedia should be a factual source of information. So far, many have requested the removal or alteration of &lt;em&gt;engineer&lt;/em&gt; from his semi-protected Wikipedia page&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to no avail; being famous apparently comes with its fair share of fans (or is it fanboys?&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;). With this article I would like to make this quarrel more known outside Wikipedia and explain why Elon Musk is not an &lt;em&gt;engineer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;why-elon-musk-is-not-an-engineer&quot;&gt;Why Elon Musk is not an engineer&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;People in favor of Elon Musk being an engineer refer to an article by the American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME).&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; In this article, a biography on Musk is provided that contains the following quote:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’m an engineer, so what I do is engineering. That’s what I’m good at.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;You have guessed it, this is a quote from Elon himself. This is where Elon being an engineer comes from. But claiming you are an engineer, does not really make you an engineer, does it? The same article even states right above the quote that he holds no engineering degree. And in the introduction he is referred to as &lt;em&gt;practical&lt;/em&gt; engineer. (okay that seems to be an actual degree in Israel&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I doubt Elon earned that)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some editors on Wikipedia argue that because of the article, those who favor removal or alteration should provide references that Elon Musk is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; an engineer. That seems to be a bit backwards to me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;differences-across-the-world&quot;&gt;Differences across the world&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;I believe the controversy stems from the title of engineer being treated differently across the world. Here in Europe, &lt;em&gt;engineer&lt;/em&gt; tends to be a title that you can only carry after earning a master’s degree. Some jurisdictions protect the title as much as &lt;em&gt;doctor&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;lawyer&lt;/em&gt;, etc. In the US, you can become a certified &lt;em&gt;Professional Engineer&lt;/em&gt;, but are apparently free to call yourself an engineer. In the UK, the public seems to equate an engineer with a car mechanic or repair man. In my opinion however, an engineer is someone who has gone through years of training and has obtained a master’s degree in engineering. Besides, you would typically be a certain type of engineer, not just an engineer by itself. (for example, a &lt;em&gt;civil&lt;/em&gt; engineer)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;what-engineer-would-elon-musk-be&quot;&gt;What engineer would Elon Musk be?&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Elon Musk did an undergraduate in Physics and Economics. This does not make you an engineer in my book. But even if we assume that Elon Musk would be an engineer, then what would be his type? Would he be a mechanical engineer? A chemical engineer? An aerospace engineer? There is no evidence that Musk actually (partly) designed any of the creations his companies spawned. As you might know, he created a video game at age 12.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He would be thus more likely be a software engineer. As that is a more recent type of engineering, the title seems to be less protected. Still, similar arguments hold against Musk being labeled engineer. And with Elon’s presence on social media, I would label him more of a social engineer: someone who tries to influence the attitude and behavior of groups.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt; &lt;figure class=&quot;image&quot;&gt; &lt;picture&gt; &lt;source srcset=&quot;/assets/images/posts/elonmusk/elon_musk_tweet.webp&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/elonmusk/elon_musk_tweet.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Social engineer displaying the Dunning-Kruger effect: when people with low ability at a task overestimate their ability&quot; /&gt; &lt;/picture&gt; &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Social engineer displaying the Dunning-Kruger effect: when people with low ability at a task overestimate their ability&lt;/figcaption&gt; &lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/elonmusk/elon_musk_tweet&quot; alt=&quot;Social engineer displaying the Dunning-Kruger effect: when people with low ability at a task overestimate their ability&quot;&gt;--&gt; &lt;/figure&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;last-words&quot;&gt;Last words&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hopefully this example creates more awareness for fallacies that are also present on Wikipedia. (I would label this example a case of &lt;em&gt;argumentum ad populum&lt;/em&gt; or appeal to the people: if many believe so, it is so&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) Form your own opinions and feel free to share what you think in the comments below. I hope you also participate on Wikipedia’s Elon Musk &lt;em&gt;Talk&lt;/em&gt; page.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am not against Elon Musk and whatever mission he is on. With this example, I would just like to point out that Wikipedia might not be as objective as it may appear. Given that many often rely only on Wikipedia pages nowadays (me included) to learn more about a certain topic, this could have serious consequences.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elon_Musk&quot;&gt;Elon Musk on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Protection_policy#semi&quot;&gt;More on semi-protected Wikipedia articles&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fav.me/db6w0dh&quot;&gt;The difference between fans and fanboys&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20181119011009/https://www.asme.org/career-education/early-career-engineers/me-today/engineer-in-focus-elon-musk&quot;&gt;ASME article on Musk at Web Archive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Practical_engineer&quot;&gt;Practical engineer on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Elon Musk’s video game is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2015/6/9/8752333/elon-musk-blastar-pc-game&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blastar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and it is ported to the web &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can read more about argumentum ad populum on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Argumentum_ad_populum&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; (the irony…) &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Participate in the discussion about Elon Musk being an engineer or not on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Talk:Elon_Musk&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>ietsism</name></author><category term="blog"/><category term="Elon Musk"/><category term="engineer"/><category term="Wikipedia"/><summary type="html">Search online for Elon Musk and one of the first things you will find is his Wikipedia page.1 The first sentence reads as follows: Elon Musk on Wikipedia &amp;#8617;</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/assets/images/posts/elonmusk/musk.jpg"/><media:content medium="image" url="https://www.ietsism.net/pages/ietsism/assets/images/posts/elonmusk/musk.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"/></entry></feed>